<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello, I am cube ! on cube</title>
    <link>https://thedataareclean.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello, I am cube ! on cube</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>CC BY 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thedataareclean.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Netlify</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day02/01-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day02/01-netlify/</guid>
      <description>So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been leveraging GitHub Pages for publishing. This works great, but for blogdown we&amp;rsquo;ll start using Netlify. Let&amp;rsquo;s start RIGHT NOW with a site we&amp;rsquo;ve already built and published.
Pre-requisites     Pick either your postcards site, or your distill site from day 01. Refresh your memory- which repository was it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GitHub profile</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day01/01-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day01/01-github/</guid>
      <description>Profile     https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/personalizing-your-profile
Pin projects to profile     https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/pinning-items-to-your-profile
Profile README     This is new! Let&amp;rsquo;s do it:
https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/managing-your-profile-readme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prework</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/prework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/prework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Introducing Yourself Online workshop! We look forward to meeting you. Before attending the workshop, please complete the following prework.
Set up RStudio Cloud     Sign up for a free RStudio Cloud account at https://rstudio.cloud/ before the workshop. I recommend logging in with an existing Google or GitHub account, if you have one (rather than creating a new account with another password you have to remember).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A postcard</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day01/02-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day01/02-postcards/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the postcards package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) [1] ‘0.2.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the blogdown package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdoown&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A distill site</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day01/03-distill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day01/03-distill/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the distill package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;)  Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  &amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt; packageVersion(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.2’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm woolen mittens</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/collection/day02/03-blogdown/index.md  To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: collection  My layout is: single-series   part 2!     does this work?      now for some very cool things     more     get ready!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Istri Project</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/project/istri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/project/istri/</guid>
      <description>Background     Ironing nano-entrepreneurs (vyapaaris) in India are stationed at every neighbourhood, collecting clothes from the local residents and ironing them. These vyapaaris primarily work with Coal iron boxes, where coal is the input fuel that heats the boxes. This product has not evolved in decades. The current product and market conditions make it difficult for vyapaaris to sustain and grow their businesses.
Every morning vyapaaris spend nearly 2 hours to heat up coal, taking up time to iron more clothes or earn additional income.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spam gushes through the cracks in Trai’s Do Not Disturb dam</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-04-29-dnd-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-04-29-dnd-calls/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article was originally published on The Ken website and is subject to their copyright terms and conditions.
Summary       Nearly 15 years after setting up the National Do Not Call Registry (NDNC), subscribers continue to be pestered by telemarketing calls
  The demand for subscriber contact details has even spawned a thriving industry of data brokers who trade subscribers’ details to telemarketers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The community-shaped hole in Skillshare’s plan to take on FrontRow, Unlu</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-04-04-skillshare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-04-04-skillshare/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article was originally published on The Ken website and is subject to their copyright terms and conditions.
Summary       Skillshare is the latest entrant in India’s creative learning market. The 12-year-old company has over 13 million registered users globally
  Skillshare is partnering with popular Indian creators like illustrator Alicia Souza, while also offering huge discounts and free trials to attract users</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AICTE to HECI: Alphabet soup for India’s autonomy-starved technical institutions</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-03-15-aicte-heci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-03-15-aicte-heci/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article was originally published on The Ken website and is subject to their copyright terms and conditions.
Summary       Established in 1945 to improve the quality of technical education in India, AICTE’s authority has expanded, often at the expense of the autonomy of engineering colleges
  AICTE’s reach is so thorough that engineering colleges have been restricted in much of their operations from curriculum design to interdisciplinary research</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hasura’s biggest open source strength is its greatest commercial weakness</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-04-22-hasura/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-04-22-hasura/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article was originally published on The Ken website and is subject to their copyright terms and conditions.
Summary       In February, Hasura became the first open source business out of India to turn unicorn
  Being an open source business, the company’s core product is available for anyone to use without paying Hasura a cent
  Hasura has built a strong community of contributors that fix bugs, build new features, and even help improve the documentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The speed bumps in LEAD’s plan to digitise India’s budget private schools</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-02-22-lead-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-02-22-lead-schools/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article was originally published on The Ken website and is subject to their copyright terms and conditions.
Summary       In the last two years, LEAD has expanded from 600 partner schools to nearly 5,000; it raised $100 million recently, becoming a unicorn in the process
  Teachers are the centre of its plans to digitise classrooms—by removing the management and lesson planning headache, LEAD lets them focus on teaching</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond WhiteHat Jr: the hinterland niche calling India’s coding edtechs</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-02-08-coding-edtech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-02-08-coding-edtech/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article was originally published on The Ken website and is subject to their copyright terms and conditions.
Summary       Coding education in India is in the midst of a boom with the addressable market is pegged at ~20 million students
  Along with growth, challenges like homogeneity of offerings, inaccessible products, and low quality teaching have plagued the industry
  The classroom size and the role of the instructor need needs to be reevaluated for coding education to expand</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon’s steep learning curve in India’s crowded online test prep market</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-01-05-amazon-academy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2022-01-05-amazon-academy/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article was originally published on The Ken website and is subject to their copyright terms and conditions.
Summary       Amazon is the latest edtech entrant in India, with its eye on the engineering and medical test prep market, and beyond
  The company is taking a no-frills approach to teaching and relying on data to organise, personalise, and present the content better</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up in the air: The vague Byju’s-NITI Aayog stab at public edtech</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2021-12-08-niti-byjus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/the-ken/2021-12-08-niti-byjus/</guid>
      <description>Note: This article was originally published on The Ken website and is subject to their copyright terms and conditions.
Summary       The $20 billion edtech giant Byju’s has set its sight on the public education system in India. It has a willing partner in NITI Aayog
  Byju’s wants to target students in India’s most developmentally challenged states; its products aren’t a great fit for the audience</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratising Action for Attainment</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/project/noral/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/project/noral/</guid>
      <description>Background      The Northern Alliance of Scotland is a regional improvement collaborative, spanning across and supporting eight local authorities and their associated school settings to improve education and reduce the poverty related attainment gap. Within these settings, children, young people and their families live across a diverse range of urban and rural settlements.
The aim of this collaboration is to determine what data sources and analytical techniques best reflect the challenges of child poverty, and subsequently provide a means to assess the poverty related attainment gap as a result – which will further allow individual school settings, local authorities and other bodies to plan targeted interventions to reduce it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Following The Education Financing Breadcrumbs</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/cdl/2021-05-10-ed-definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/cdl/2021-05-10-ed-definition/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Gautam Arora from Unsplash.
COVID-19 has had an unprecedented impact affecting a large number of children across states, class, caste, gender and region. In India, school closures have affected 320 million students and only 37.6 million children across 16 states were able to continue education through various initiatives such as online classrooms and radio programmes etc. 1 A survey by Save the Children during the pandemic reported the discontinuation of children’s education in 62% of the surveyed households with 67% in rural and 55% in urban areas, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl Education Spending Tracker</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/project/girl-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/project/girl-ed/</guid>
      <description>Background      CivicDataLab partnered with HAQ: Centre for Child Rights (HAQ-CRC) and Malala Fund on a project to strengthen financial accountability towards girl education in Uttar Pradesh. The project aims at monitoring the financing of education related scheme with a special focus on promoting girl education in the state. This project will serve as a means to measure the progress towards SDG Goal 4 &amp;amp; 6 and will also strengthen accountability measures in public financing of education by creating a knowledge pool which will further help policy making to promote girl education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Ingress &amp; rise of Ed-Tech in the COVID-19 Era</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/cdl/2021-02-18-budget-reco-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/cdl/2021-02-18-budget-reco-ed/</guid>
      <description>Photo by marif shaik from Unsplash.
COVID-19 and Education   The COVID-19 pandemic changed the education landscape of India overnight. Educational institutes were compelled to adopt various digital learning alternatives to sustain timely growth of children. In a country where only 4.4% of rural and 23.4% of urban households own computers, the challenge becomes even bigger. Moreover, this gap gets wider with only 42% of urban households having a computer with an internet connection, and the same being available to only 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of FOSS in India Report</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/project/foss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/project/foss/</guid>
      <description>Background      CivicDataLab in partnership with Omidyar Network India conducted a research study to develop a deeper understanding of the Free &amp;amp; Open Source Software (FOSS) ecosystem of India, its current stakeholders, challenges faced by the FOSS movement, and explore ways to support FOSS communities and accelerate adoption in India. The research also chronicles the journey of FOSS in India, research and map out the pioneers of the FOSS movement: tracing projects, local communities, big tech contributors and current adoption by State and Central Governments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening Financial Accountability towards Girl Education</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/cdl/2020-12-23-girl-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/blog/cdl/2020-12-23-girl-ed/</guid>
      <description>Girl Education and India   Although education is a fundamental right in India, according to Census 2011, 1 in 4 children of school going age is out of school in our country and 99 million children in total have dropped out of school in the last 10 years. Out of every 100 children, only 32 children finish their school education age-appropriately (DISE 2014–15). The Govt. has achieved universal enrollment in primary school but dropout rate is 4% in elementary school, rising to 17% in secondary school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StoryWeaver</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/project/storyweaver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/project/storyweaver/</guid>
      <description>Background     In a world where six out of every ten children are not achieving minimum proficiency in reading and mathematics, the road to literacy – and UN Sustainable Development Goal 4, quality education – is an uphill climb. And while the obstacles are many – including a shortage of schools and teachers for millions of children, compounded by a dearth of local language reading material for 40% of students – Pratham Books’ StoryWeaver is committed to providing children with the very first step to literacy acquisition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes   A A A A A A A A   6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px)     Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:
   Desirée De Leon 🦒 (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)
   Garrick Aden-Buie 🧙‍♀️ (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)
   Allison Horst 🐕 (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot 🦔)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://thedataareclean.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thedataareclean.com/license/</guid>
      <description>Unless stated otherwise, most of my work is released under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC BY 4.0) License.
 You are free to:     Share — copy and redistribute the material in any medium or format
  Adapt — remix, transform, and build upon the material for any purpose, even commercially.
  The licensor cannot revoke these freedoms as long as you follow the license terms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
