<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on cube</title>
    <link>https://www.thedataareclean.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on cube</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>CC BY 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.thedataareclean.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Following The Education Financing Breadcrumbs</title>
      <link>https://www.thedataareclean.com/blog/2021-05-10-ed-definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thedataareclean.com/blog/2021-05-10-ed-definition/</guid>
      <description>knitr::include_graphics(&amp;quot;image.jpg&amp;quot;) _Figure from Unsplash{target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;} by Gautam Arora{target=&amp;quot;blank&amp;quot;}.
COVID-19 has had an unprecedented impact affecting a large number of children across states, class, caste, gender and region. In India, school closures have affected 320 million students and only 37.6 million children across 16 states were able to continue education through various initiatives such as online classrooms and radio programmes etc. ^[Education: From disruption to recovery, UNESCO, accessed on 7th May, 2021, https://en.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Ingress &amp; rise of Ed-Tech in the COVID-19 Era</title>
      <link>https://www.thedataareclean.com/blog/2021-02-18-budget-reco-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thedataareclean.com/blog/2021-02-18-budget-reco-ed/</guid>
      <description>Photo by marif shaik from Unsplash.
COVID-19 and Education   The COVID-19 pandemic changed the education landscape of India overnight. Educational institutes were compelled to adopt various digital learning alternatives to sustain timely growth of children. In a country where only 4.4% of rural and 23.4% of urban households own computers, the challenge becomes even bigger. Moreover, this gap gets wider with only 42% of urban households having a computer with an internet connection, and the same being available to only 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening Financial Accountability towards Girl Education</title>
      <link>https://www.thedataareclean.com/blog/2020-12-23-girl-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.thedataareclean.com/blog/2020-12-23-girl-ed/</guid>
      <description>Girl Education and India   Although education is a fundamental right in India, according to Census 2011, 1 in 4 children of school going age is out of school in our country and 99 million children in total have dropped out of school in the last 10 years. Out of every 100 children, only 32 children finish their school education age-appropriately (DISE 2014–15). The Govt. has achieved universal enrollment in primary school but dropout rate is 4% in elementary school, rising to 17% in secondary school.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
